Guide to the Cornell University Department of Geology records, 1875-1957.
Cornell University Department of Geology records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University Department of Geology records, 1875-1957.
14-15-728
Cornell University. Department of Geology.
2 cubic feet.
Correspondence, reports, abtracts, registers, and other records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The papers of the Geology Department consist of examination reports, reptints, abstracts of geology lectures, estimates of departmental needs, registers of geology students (1947, 1957), issues of the department newsletter (spelled "news letter"), and other records and correspondence.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The papers of the Geology Department consist of examination reports, abstracts of geology lectures, estimates of departmental needs, registers of geology students (1947, 1957), issues of the department newsletter (spelled "news letter"), and other records and correspondence, including letters and copies of letters to and/or from George Francis Atkinson, Thomas Frederick Crane, Adam Capen Gill, Gilbert Dennison Harris, Heinrich Ries, Jacob Gould Schurman, Ralph Stockman Tarr, Walter Francis Willcox, Henry Shaler Williams, and others. Also reprints from Department faculty.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University. Department of Geology.; Atkinson, George Francis, 1854-1918.; Crane, Thomas Frederick, 1844-1927.; Gill, Adam Capen.; Harris, Gilbert D. (Gilbert Dennison), 1864-1952.; Ries, Heinrich, 1871-1951.; Schurman, Jacob Gould, 1854-1942.; Tarr, Ralph S. (Ralph Stockman), 1864-1912.; Willcox, Walter Francis, 1861-1964.; Williams, Henry Shaler, 1847-1918.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University. Department of Geology. News letter.
Subjects:
Geology--Study and teaching, Higher.; Geologists.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence, examinations, and other records, Dec. 1901-Dec. 1904 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, examinations, and other records, Jan. 1905 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, examinations, and other records, Feb.-Mar. 1905 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, examinations, and other records, Apr. 1905 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, examinations, and other records, May 1905 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, examinations, and other records, June 1905 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, examinations, and other records, July-Oct. 1905 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, examinations, and other records, Nov.-Dec. 1905 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, examinations, and other records, 1904-1905 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, examinations, and other records, Jan. 1906 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, examinations, and other records, Feb.-Mar. 1906 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, examinations, and other records, Apr. 1906 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, examinations, and other records, May 1906 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, examinations, and other records, June 1906 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, examinations, and other records, July-Dec. 1906 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, examinations, and other records, 1905-1906 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, examinations, and other records, Jan.-Apr. 1907 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, examinations, and other records, May-Aug. 1907 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, examinations, and other records, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Miscelaneous, notes, and reports. Includes report on the adjustment of McGraw Hall, annual reports, inventory of the department, term information.., 1905-1907 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- T.B. Comstock abstract of lectures, 1870s (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Geology Department abstract of lectures, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Geology Department News Letter, Dec. 1947, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Geology Department registers, 1947, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Register 1868-1947 and News Letters 1947-1951 (Box 1)
- McGraw Hall and the Department of Geology - Excerpts from the Cornell Era, 1880-1881 (Box 1)
- McGraw Hall and the Department of Geology - Excerpts from the Cornell Era, 1882-1890 (Box 1)
- Bound volumes of reprints by Department of Geology faculty or otherwise related to the Department, 1871-1957
  An index to the reprints is available here. This 5MB PDF guide scanned from the table of contents of each volume.
  - Reprints - Department of Geology (1-37), 1871-1902 (Box 1)
  - Reprints - Department of Geology (38-58), 1902-1908 (Box 1)
  - Reprints - Department of Geology (59-95), 1908-1917 (Box 1)
  - Reprints - Department of Geology (96-136), 1917-1925 (Box 1)
  - Reprints - Department of Geology (137-158), 1925-1926 (Box 2)
  - Reprints - Department of Geology (159-200), 1926-1930 (Box 2)
  - Reprints - Department of Geology (201-241), 1931-1934 (Box 2)
  - Reprints - Department of Geology (242-282), 1934-1937 (Box 2)
  - Reprints - Department of Geology (283-305), 1937-1940 (Box 2)
  - Reprints - Department of Geology (306-322), 1940-1943 (Box 2)
  - Reprints - Department of Geology (323-347), 1943-1949 (Box 2)
  - Reprints - Department of Geology (348-366), 1950-1953 (Box 2)
  - Reprints - Department of Geology (367-385), 1953-1957 (Box 2)